<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Kategorier>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#140 — Burning Down the Fourth Estate</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Matt Taibbi about the state journalism and the polarization of our politics. They discuss the controversy over Steve Bannon at the New Yorker Festival, monetizing the Trump phenomenon, the Jamal Kashoggi murder, the Kavanaugh hearing, the Rolling Stone reporting on the UVA rape case, the viability of a political center, the 2020 Presidential election, the Russia investigation, our vanishing attention span, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p1"&gt;You can support the Waking Up Podcast and receive subscriber-only content at &lt;a href= "https://samharris.org/subscribe/"&gt;&lt;span class= "s1"&gt;SamHarris.org/subscribe&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_140_Taibbi_Final_.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>112211410</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#139 — Sacred &amp; Profane</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris gets together with Bill Maher and Larry Charles to celebrate the 10th anniversary of their film "Religulous." They discuss religion, politics, comedy, and other dangerous topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up Podcast and receive subscriber-only content at &lt;a href= "https://samharris.org/subscribe/"&gt;SamHarris.org/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_139_Maher_Charles.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>118852255</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>Introducing the Waking Up Course</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the podcast, Sam Harris introduces the Waking Up Course. More information can be found at &lt;a href= "https://wakingup.com/"&gt;WakingUp.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Introducing_the_Waking_Up_Course.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>10354532</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#138 — The Edge of Humanity</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Yuval Noah Harari about his new book “21 Lessons for the 21st Century.” They discuss the importance of meditation for his intellectual life, the primacy of stories, the need to revise our fundamental assumptions about human civilization, the threats to liberal democracy, a world without work, universal basic income, the virtues of nationalism, the implications of AI and automation, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up Podcast and receive subscriber-only content at &lt;a href= "https://samharris.org/subscribe/"&gt;SamHarris.org/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_138_Harari.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>122050989</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#137 — Safe Space</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Jonathan Haidt about his new book "The Coddling of the American Mind." They discuss the hostility to free speech that has grown more common among young adults, recent moral panics on campus, the role of intentions in ethical life, the economy of prestige in “call out” culture, how we should define bigotry, systemic racism, the paradox of progress, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up Podcast and receive subscriber-only content at &lt;a href= "https://samharris.org/subscribe/"&gt;SamHarris.org/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_137_Haidt.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>92202912</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#136 — Digital Humanism</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Jaron Lanier about the economics, politics, and psychology of our digital lives. They discuss the insidious idea that information should be free, what we should want from an advanced economy, the role of advertising, libertarianism in Silicon Valley, the problems with social media, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up Podcast and receive subscriber-only content at &lt;a href= "https://samharris.org/subscribe/"&gt;SamHarris.org/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_136_Lanier.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>61068492</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#135 — Navigating Sex and Gender</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Martie Haselton about sex and gender, the role of hormones in human psychology, “Darwinian feminism,” the unique hormonal experience of women, transgenderism, the Google Memo, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up Podcast and receive subscriber-only content at &lt;a href= "https://samharris.org/subscribe/"&gt;SamHarris.org/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_135_Haselton.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>86537966</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#134 — Beyond the Politics of Race</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Coleman Hughes about race, racism, and identity politics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up Podcast and receive subscriber-only content at &lt;a href= "https://samharris.org/subscribe/"&gt;SamHarris.org/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_134_Hughes.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>111401244</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#133 — Globalism on the Brink</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Ian Bremmer about the failure of globalism and rise of populism. They discuss immigration, trade, automation, wealth inequality, Trump, identity politics and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up Podcast and receive subscriber-only content at &lt;a href= "https://samharris.org/subscribe/"&gt;SamHarris.org/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_133_Bremmer.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>71239252</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#132 — Freeing the Hostages</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Chris Voss about his experience as a hostage negotiator for the FBI. They discuss different types of hostage crises, along with many of the lessons that apply to negotiating in normal life.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;You can support the Waking Up Podcast and receive subscriber-only content at &lt;a href= "https://samharris.org/subscribe/"&gt;SamHarris.org/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_132_Voss.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>74459926</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#131 — Dictators, Immigration, #MeToo, and Other Imponderables </Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Masha Gessen about Vladimir Putin, the problem of gauging public opinion in Russia, Trump's fondness for dictators, the challenges of immigration, comparisons between Christian and Muslim intolerance, "fake news" and the health of journalism, the #MeToo movement, and other topics. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;You can support the Waking Up Podcast and receive subscriber-only content at &lt;a href= "https://samharris.org/subscribe/"&gt;SamHarris.org/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_131_Gessen.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>90971077</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#130 — Universal Basic Income</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with presidential candidate Andrew Yang about "universal basic income" (UBI). They discuss the state of the economy, the rise of automation and AI, the arguments for and against UBI, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;You can support the Waking Up Podcast and receive subscriber-only content at &lt;a href= "https://samharris.org/subscribe/"&gt;SamHarris.org/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_130_Yang.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>71992452</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#129 — An Insider’s View of Medicine</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Dr. Nina Shapiro about the practice of medicine. They discuss the unique resiliency of children, the importance of second opinions, bad doctors, how medical training has changed in recent years, medical uncertainty, risk perception, vaccine safety, and other topics.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;You can support the Waking Up Podcast and receive subscriber-only content at &lt;a href= "https://samharris.org/subscribe/"&gt;SamHarris.org/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_129_Shapiro.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>73456512</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#128 — Transformations of Mind</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Geoffrey Miller about evolutionary psychology. They discuss sexual selection, virtue signaling, social media, public shaming, monogamy and polyamory, taboo topics in science, genetic engineering, gender differences and the “Google memo,” moral psychology, existential risk, AI, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p1"&gt;You can support the Waking Up Podcast and receive subscriber-only content at &lt;a href= "https://samharris.org/subscribe/"&gt;SamHarris.org/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_128_Miller.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>151681180</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#127 — Freedom from the Known</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Michael Pollan about his new book “How to Change Your Mind.” They cover the the resurgence of interest in psychedelics in clinical practice and end-of-life care, the “betterment of well people,” the relationship between thinking and mental suffering, the differences between psychedelics and meditation, the non-duality of consciousness, the brain’s “default mode network,” their experiences with various psychedelics, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up Podcast and receive subscriber-only content at &lt;a href= "https://samharris.org/subscribe/"&gt;SamHarris.org/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_127_Pollan.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>84521105</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#126 — In Defense of Honor</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast Sam Harris speaks with Tamler Sommers about cultures of honor. They discuss the difference between honor and dignity, “justice porn,” honor killings, honor and interpersonal violence, prison and gang culture, collective responsibility and collective punishment, retributive vs restorative justice, the ethics of forgiveness and redemption, #metoo, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p1"&gt;You can support the Waking Up Podcast and receive subscriber-only content at &lt;a href= "https://samharris.org/subscribe/"&gt;SamHarris.org/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_126_Sommers.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>126370476</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#125 — What Is Christianity?</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks to Bart Ehrman about his experience of being a born-again Christian, his academic training in New Testament scholarship, his loss of faith, the most convincing argument in defense of Christianity, the status of miracles, the composition of the New Testament, the resurrection of Jesus, the nature of heaven and hell, the book of Revelation, the End Times, self-contradictions in the Bible, the concept of a messiah, whether Jesus actually existed, Christianity as a cult of human sacrifice, the conversion of Constantine, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up Podcast and receive subscriber-only content at &lt;a href= "https://samharris.org/subscribe/"&gt;SamHarris.org/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_125_Ehrman.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>113112704</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#124 — In Search of Reality</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Sean Carroll about our understanding of reality. They discuss consciousness, the many worlds view of quantum mechanics, the arrow of time, free will, facts and values, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up Podcast and receive subscriber-only content at &lt;a href= "https://samharris.org/subscribe/"&gt;SamHarris.org/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_124_Carroll.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>113429489</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#123 — Identity &amp; Honesty</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Ezra Klein, Editor-at-Large for Vox Media, about racism, identity politics, intellectual honesty, and the controversy over his podcast with Charles Murray (Waking Up #73). &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up Podcast and receive subscriber-only content at &lt;a href= "https://samharris.org/subscribe/"&gt;SamHarris.org/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_123_Klein.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>126648375</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#122 — Extreme Housekeeping Edition</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris responds to the ongoing controversy over his interview with Charles Murray and discusses his upcoming conversation with Ezra Klein. He also announces a change he will be making to the format of the podcast.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up Podcast and receive subscriber-only content at &lt;a href= "https://samharris.org/subscribe/"&gt;SamHarris.org/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_122_Extreme_Housekeeping_Edition.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>42178620</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#121 — White Power</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Christian Picciolini about his experience as a neo-Nazi skinhead. They discuss how Christian got out of the movement, the limits of shame and forgiveness, the cult-like dynamics of white supremacy, the alt-Right, Russian support for white supremacy in the US, “fake news”, the significance of Charlottesville, the SPLC, and many other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p1"&gt;You can support the Waking Up Podcast and receive subscriber-only content at &lt;a href= "https://samharris.org/subscribe/"&gt;SamHarris.org/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Picciolini_Re-edit_V2.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>137666006</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#120 — What Is and What Matters</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Rebecca Goldstein and Max Tegmark about the foundations of human knowledge and morality.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up Podcast and receive subscriber-only content at &lt;a href= "https://samharris.org/subscribe/"&gt;SamHarris.org/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_120_Goldstein_Tegmark.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>111150260</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#119 — Hidden Motives</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Robin Hanson about our hidden motives in everyday life. They discuss s&lt;/span&gt;elfishness, hypocrisy, norms and meta-norms, cheating, deception, self-deception,&lt;span class= "Apple-converted-space"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;education, the evolutionary logic of conversation, social status, signaling and counter-signaling, common knowledge, AI, and many other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p1"&gt;You can support the Waking Up Podcast and receive subscriber-only content at &lt;a href= "https://samharris.org/subscribe/"&gt;SamHarris.org/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p2"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_119_Hanson.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>136279336</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel># 118 — The View from Trumpistan</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Preet Bharara about President Trump and the Russia investigation. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://samharris.org/subscribe/"&gt;SamHarris.org/subscribe.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Supporters get exclusive access to Sam's &lt;a href= "https://samharris.org/ama-answers/"&gt;AMA episodes&lt;/a&gt; and other subscriber-only content.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_118_Bharara.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>66476921</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#117 — Networks, Power, and Chaos</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Niall Ferguson about his new book "The Square and the Tower." They discuss his career as a writer, networks and hierarchies, how history gets written, the similarity between the 16th century and the 21st, the role of social media in the 2016 Presidential election, the influence of advertising on the public sphere, Trump, the Russian investigation, Islamic extremism, counterfactuals, what would have happened if Clinton had won the presidency, immigration in Europe, conspiracy theories, capitalism, globalization, communism, wealth inequality, universal basic income, Henry Kissinger, the prospect of a US war with China, cyberwar, and other topics.&lt;span class= "Apple-converted-space"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-converted-space"&gt;You support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://samharris.org/subscribe/"&gt;SamHarris.org/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;.   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_117_Ferguson.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>118240743</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>The Russell Brand Interview</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;This episode of the Waking Up podcast features an interview that Sam did with Russell Brand on the Under the Skin podcast. They speak about religion, terrorism, politics, meditation, psychedelics, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://samharris.org/support/"&gt;SamHarris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/The_Russell_Brand_Interview.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>116170394</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#116 — AI: Racing Toward the Brink</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Eliezer Yudkowsky about the nature of intelligence, different types of AI, the "alignment problem," IS vs OUGHT, the possibility that future AI might deceive us, the AI arms race, conscious AI, coordination problems, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://samharris.org/support/"&gt;SamHarris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_116_Yudkowsky.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>125628810</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#115 — Sam Harris, Lawrence Krauss, and Matt Dillahunty (1)</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Lawrence Krauss and Matt Dillahunty about the threat of nuclear war, Christian support for Trump, science and a universal conception of morality, the role of intuition in science, the primacy of consciousness, the nature of time, free will, the self, meditation, and other topics. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p1"&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://samharris.org/support/"&gt;SamHarris.org/support.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_115_Krauss_Dillahunty.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>96160964</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#114 — Politics and Sanity</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with David Frum and Andrew Sullivan about the Trump presidency, hyper-partisanship, how democracies fail, immigration, the lowering life expectancy in the U.S., racism, social media, the opioid crisis, marijuana legalization, religion, what a healthy politics might look like, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p1"&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://samharris.org/support/"&gt;SamHarris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_114_Frum_Sullivan.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>133197928</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#113 — Consciousness and the Self</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Anil Seth about the scientific study of consciousness, where consciousness emerges in nature, levels of consciousness, perception as a “controlled hallucination,” emotion, the experience of “pure consciousness,” consciousness as “integrated information,” measures of “brain complexity,” psychedelics, different aspects of the “self,” conscious AI, and many other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p1"&gt;You can support the Waking Up at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;SamHarris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_113_Seth.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>185015180</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#112 — The Intellectual Dark Web</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Eric Weinstein and Ben Shapiro about the breakdown of shared values, the problem with identity politics, religion, free will, the primacy of reason, and many other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p1"&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;SamHarris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_112_Weinstein_ShapiroMONO.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>136634124</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#111 — The Science of Meditation</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Daniel Goleman and Richard J. Davidson about the current scientific understanding of meditation practice. They speak about the original stigma associated with meditation, the history of introspection in eastern and western cultures, the recent collaboration between Buddhism and western science, the difference between altered states and altered traits, an alternate conception of mental health, “meta-awareness,” the relationship between mindfulness and “flow,” the difference between pain and suffering, mindfulness-based stress reduction (MBSR),&lt;span class= "Apple-converted-space"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;SamHarris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_111_Goleman_Davidson.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>84372360</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#110 — The Change Artist</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with AJ Jacobs about religion, gossip, polyamory, health advice, our past and future selves, “radical honesty,” human genealogy, tribalism, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p1"&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;SamHarris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_110_Jacobs.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>108780564</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#109— Biology and Culture</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Bret Weinstein about the moral panic at Evergreen State College, the concept of race, genetic differences between human populations, intersectionality, sex and gender, “metaphorical truth,” religion and “group selection,” equality, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p1"&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;SamHarris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_109_Seattle.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>123852390</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#108 — Defending the Experts</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Tom Nichols about his book &lt;em&gt;The Death of Expertise&lt;/em&gt;. They discuss the “Dunning-Kruger Effect,” the growth of knowledge and reliance on authority, when experts fail, the repudiation of expertise in politics, conspiracy thinking, North Korea, Trump, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;SamHarris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_108_Nichols.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>94408893</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#107 — Is Life Actually Worth Living?</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with David Benatar about his philosophy of “anti-natalism." They discuss the asymmetry between the good and bad things in life, the ethics of existential risk, the moral landscape, the limits and paradoxes of introspection, the “experience machine” thought experiment, population ethics, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p1"&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;SamHarris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_107_Benatar.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>111511525</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#106 — Humanity 2.0</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Jennifer Doudna about the gene-editing technology CRISPR/cas9. They talk about the biology of gene editing, how specific tissues in the body can be targeted, the ethical implications of changing the human genome, the importance of curiosity-driven science, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p1"&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;SamHarris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_106_Doudna.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>46401028</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#105 — Richard Dawkins, Sam Harris, and Matt Dillahunty</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;The following conversation between Richard Dawkins, Sam Harris, and Matt Dillahunty was recorded at the Orpheum Theatre in Vancouver on November 2, 2017.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;SamHarris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_105_Dawkins_Harris_Dillahunty_Vancouver.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>94142241</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#104 — The Lessons of Death</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Frank Ostaseski about death and dying—and about how the awareness of death can improve our lives in each moment.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;SamHarris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_104_Ostaseski.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>65278223</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#103 — American Fantasies</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Kurt Andersen about the American aptitude for unfounded belief, the religious lunacy of the Puritans, populist mistrust of authority, the link between postmodernism and religious fundamentalism, the unique history of American religious entrepreneurship, the Trump phenomenon, the effect of fame on politics, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;SamHarris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_103_Andersen.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>68531653</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#102 — Is Buddhism True?</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Robert Wright about his book &lt;em&gt;Why Buddhism is True: The Science and Philosophy of Meditation and Enlightenment&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;SamHarris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_102_Wright.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>127728405</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#101 — Defending the Republic</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Cass Sunstein about the polarization and fragmentation of American society, “choice architecture,” the importance of face-to-face interactions for problem solving, group polarization and identity politics, virtuous extremism, the wisdom of crowds, direct democracy, the limits of free speech, the process of Presidential impeachment, and other topics. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_101_Sunstein.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>78901461</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#100 — Facing the Crowd</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Nicholas Christakis about mob behavior, moral panics, and current threats to free speech.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;SamHarris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_100_Christakis.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>97284349</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>The "After On" Interview</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;This episode of the Waking Up podcast features an interview that Sam Harris did with Rob Reid on the After On podcast. They speak about publishing, psychedelics, terrorism, meditation, free speech and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;SamHarris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/After_On.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>103640817</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#99 — What Happened to Liberalism?</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Mark Lilla about the fate of political liberalism in the United States, the emergence of a new identity politics, the role of class in American society, wealth inequality, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p1"&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_99_Lilla.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>74502108</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#98 — Into the Dark Land</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Siddhartha Mukherjee about his Pulitzer Prize winning book, &lt;em&gt;The Emperor of All Maladies: A Biography of Cancer&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_98_Mukherjee.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>67054071</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#97 — The Impossible War</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Ken Burns and Lynn Novick about their latest film, The Vietnam War.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_97_BurnsNovick.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>59028884</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#96 — The Nature of Consciousness</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Thomas Metzinger about the scientific and experiential understanding of consciousness. They also talk about the significance of WWII for the history of ideas, the role of intuition in science, the ethics of building conscious AI, the self as an hallucination, how we identify with our thoughts, attention as the root of the feeling of self, the place of Eastern philosophy in Western science, and the limitations of secular humanism.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_96_Metzinger.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>109783644</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#95 — What You Need to Know About Climate Change</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Joseph Romm about how the climate is changing and how we know that human behavior is the primary cause. They discuss why small changes in temperature matter so much, the threats of sea-level rise and desertification, the best and worst case scenarios, the Paris Climate Agreement, the politics surrounding climate science, and many other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_95_Romm.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>121785716</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#94 — The Future of Intelligence</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Max Tegmark about his new book &lt;em&gt;Life 3.0: Being Human in the Age of Artificial Intelligence&lt;/em&gt;. They talk about the nature of intelligence, the risks of superhuman AI, a nonbiological definition of life, the substrate independence of minds, the relevance and irrelevance of consciousness for the future of AI, near-term breakthroughs in AI, and other topics.  &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_94_Tegmark.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>85431847</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#93 — Identity &amp; Terror</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Douglas Murray about identity politics, the rise of white nationalism, the events in Charlottesville, guilt by association, the sources of western values, the problem of finding meaning in a secular world, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_93_Murray.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>85963770</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#92 — The Limits of Persuasion</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with David Pizarro and Tamler Sommers about free speech on campus, the Scott Adams podcast, the failings of the mainstream media, moral persuasion, moral certainty, the ethics of abortion, Buddhism, the illusion of the self, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p1"&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_92_Very_Bad_Wizards.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>135187968</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#91 — The Biology of Good and Evil</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Robert Sapolsky about his work with baboons, the opposition between reason and emotion, doubt, the evolution of the brain, the civilizing role of the frontal cortex, the illusion of free will, justice and vengeance, brain-machine interface, religion, drugs, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_91_Robert_Sapolsky.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>94300443</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#90 — Living With Violence</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Gavin de Becker about the primacy of human intuition in the prediction and prevention of violence.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_90_deBecker_fix.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>135981324</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#89 — On Becoming a Better Person</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with David Brooks about his book &lt;em&gt;The Road to Character&lt;/em&gt;, the importance of words like “sin” and "virtue," self-esteem vs. self-overcoming, the significance of keeping promises, honesty, President Trump, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_89_David_Brooks.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>55902762</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#88 — Must We Accept a Nuclear North Korea?</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Mark Bowden about the problem of a nuclear-armed North Korea.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_88_Mark_Bowden.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>66308626</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#87 — Triggered </Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris and Scott Adams debate the character and competence of President Trump.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_87_Scott_Adams.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>131918846</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#86 — From Cells to Cities</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Geoffrey West about how biological and social systems scale, the significance of fractals, the prospects of radically extending human life, the concept of “emergence” in complex systems, the importance of cities, the necessity for continuous innovation, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p1"&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_86_Geoffrey_West.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>124340039</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#85 — Is this the End of Europe?</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Douglas Murray about his book &lt;em&gt;The Strange Death of Europe: Immigration, Identity, Islam.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_85_Douglas_Murray.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>84944930</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#84 — Landscapes of Mind</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Kevin Kelly about why it’s so hard to predict future technology, the nature of intelligence, the “singularity,” artificial consciousness, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_84_Kelly.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>98941553</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#83 — The Politics of Emergency</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Fareed Zakaria about his career as a journalist, Samuel Huntington's "clash of civilizations," political partisanship, Trump, the health of the news media, the connection between Islam and intolerance, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_83_Zakaria.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>81277567</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#82 — The End of the World According to ISIS</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Graeme Wood about his experience reporting on ISIS, the myth of online recruitment, the theology of ISIS, the quality of their propaganda, the most important American recruit to the organization, the roles of Jesus and the Anti-Christ in Islamic prophecy, free speech and the ongoing threat of jihadism, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_82_Wood.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>101447548</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#81 —  Leaving Islam</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Sarah Haider about her organization Ex-Muslims of North America, how the political Left is confused about Islam, "rape culture" under Islam, honesty without bigotry, stealth theocracy, immigration, the prospects of reforming Islam, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_81_Haider.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>101524199</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#80 — The Unraveling</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with David Frum about political partisanship, recent security leaks, Trump's foreign policy, the Russia investigation, Kathy Griffin's joke, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_80_Frum.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>57745666</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#79 — The Road to Tyranny</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Timothy Snyder about his book &lt;em&gt;On Tyranny: Twenty Lessons from the Twentieth Century.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_79_Snyder.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>76205403</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#78 — Persuasion and Control</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Zeynep Tufekci about "surveillance capitalism," the Trump campaign's use of Facebook, AI-enabled marketing, the health of the press, Wikileaks, ransomware attacks, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_78_Zeynep_Tufekci.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>86175156</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#77 — The Moral Complexity of Genetics</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Siddhartha Mukherjee about the human desire to understand and manipulate heredity, the genius of Gregor Mendel, the ethics of altering our genes, the future of genetic medicine, patent issues in genetic research, controversies about race and intelligence, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_77_Mukherjee.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>127174416</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#76 — The Path to Impeachment</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Anne Applebaum and Juliette Kayyem about the unfolding Russia scandal in the White House.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_76_Applebaum_and_Kayyem.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>77069799</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#75 — Ask Me Anything 7</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris answers questions from listeners about the illusion of the self, his podcast with Charles Murray, the future of brain-machine interfaces, his BJJ practice, reasoning with the extreme Left, mindfulness and parenting, his experience of going back to school after a long break, transgenderism, increasing one’s vocabulary, and other topics.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Ask_Me_Anything_7.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>55884816</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#74 — What Should We Eat?</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Gary Taubes about his career as a science journalist, the difficulty of studying nutrition and public health scientifically, the growing epidemics of obesity and diabetes, the role of hormones in weight gain, the controversies surrounding his work, and other topics. &lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_74_Gary_Taubes.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>122206307</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#73 — Forbidden Knowledge</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Charles Murray about the controversy over his book "The Bell Curve," the validity and significance of IQ as a measure of intelligence, the problem of social stratification, the rise of Trump, universal basic income, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p1"&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p2"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_73_Charles_Murray.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>132506861</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#72 — Privacy and Security</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with General Michael V. Hayden about the reality of spying, the difference between the NSA and the CIA, the ethics of secrecy, Edward Snowden, the Russian Hacking of the 2016 US Presidential election, and other topics. &lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_72_Michael_Hayden.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>37201114</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#71 — What Is Technology Doing to Us?</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Tristan Harris about the arms race for human attention, the ethics of persuasion, the consequences of having an ad-based economy, the dynamics of regret, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_71_Tristan_Harris.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>104063031</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#70 — Beauty and Terror</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with physicist Lawrence Krauss about the utility of public debates, the progress of science, confusion about the role of consciousness in quantum mechanics, the present danger of nuclear war, the Trump administration, the relative threats of Christian theocracy and Islamism, and realistic fears about terrorism.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;www.samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_70_Lawrence_Krauss.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>131629174</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#69 — The Russia Connection</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Anne Applebaum about Russia's meddling in the U.S. Presidential election and Trump's troubling affinity for Vladimir Putin.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;SamHarris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_69_Anne_Applebaum.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>78738979</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#68 — Reality and the Imagination</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Yuval Noah Harari about meditation, the need for stories, the power of technology to erase the boundary between fact and fiction, wealth inequality, the problem of finding meaning in a world without work, religion as a virtual reality game, the difference between pain and suffering, the future of globalism, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p2"&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p1"&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;SamHarris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_68_Yuval_Harari.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>88431981</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#67 — Meaning and Chaos</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris and Jordan Peterson discuss science, religion, archetypes, mythology, and the perennial problem of finding meaning in life.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p1"&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_67_Jordan_Peterson_2.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>105430619</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#66 — Living with Robots </Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this Episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Kate Darling about the ethical concerns surrounding our increasing use of robots and other autonomous systems.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Kate Darling is a leading expert in robot ethics. She’s a researcher at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) Media Lab, where she investigates social robotics and conducts experimental studies on human-robot interaction. Kate is also a fellow at the Harvard Berkman Center for Internet &amp; Society and the Yale Information Society Project, and is an affiliate at the Institute for Ethics and Emerging Technologies. She explores the emotional connection between people and life-like machines, seeking to influence technology design and public policy. Her writing and research anticipate difficult questions that lawmakers, engineers, and the wider public will need to address as human-robot relationships evolve in the coming decades. Kate has a background in law &amp; economics and intellectual property.  &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_66_Kate_Darling.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>64255524</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#65 — We're All Cucks Now</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with David Frum about the presidency of Donald Trump.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_65_David_Frum.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>67785714</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#64 — Ask Me Anything 6</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris answers questions from listeners about his conversation with Jordan Peterson, the reaction to Milo Yiannopoulos at U.C. Berkeley, the “Muslim ban,” the echo chamber of social media, Trump’s lies, the value of the humanities, the ethics of ending aging, whether consciousness can be an illusion, evolution and morality, free speech and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_64_AMA_6.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>83780512</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#63 — Why Meditate?</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris and Joseph Goldstein answer questions about the practice of mindfulness. They discuss the nature negative emotions, the importance of ethics, the concept of enlightenment, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_63_Joseph_Goldstein.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>102437232</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#62 — What is True?</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with psychologist Jordan B. Peterson about freedom of speech and the nature of truth.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_62_Jordan_Peterson.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>130834556</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#61 — The Power of Belief</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with author Lawrence Wright about al-Qaeda &amp; ISIS, Arab culture, 9/11 conspiracy theories, the migrant crisis in Europe, Scientology, parallels between L. Ron Hubbard and Donald Trump, the Satanic cult panic, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_61_Lawrence_Wright.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>123051007</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#60 — An Evening with Richard Dawkins and Sam Harris (2)</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Richard Dawkins at a live event in Los Angeles (second of two). They discuss Richard’s experience of having a stroke, the genetic future of humanity, the analogy between genes and memes, the “extended phenotype,” Islam and bigotry, the biology of race, how to find meaning without religion, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_60_Dawkins_Live_2.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>80647939</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#59 — Friend &amp; Foe</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Maajid Nawaz about the Southern Poverty Law Center, Robert Spencer, Keith Ellison, moderate Muslims, Shadi Hamid’s notion of “Islamic exceptionalism," the migrant crisis in Europe, foreign interventions, Trump, Putin, Obama’s legacy, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_59_Maajid_Nawaz.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>112323651</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#58 — The Putin Question</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Garry Kasparov about the problem of waning American power, the rise of Putin, the coming presidency of Donald Trump, computer chess, the future of artificial intelligence, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_58_Garry_Kasparov.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>88488448</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#57 — An Evening with Richard Dawkins and Sam Harris (1)</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Richard Dawkins at a live event in Los Angeles (first of two). They cover religion, Jurassic Park, artificial intelligence, elitism, continuing human evolution, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_57_Richard_Dawkins.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>93657424</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#56 — Abusing Dolores</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Paul Bloom about empathy, meditation studies, morality, AI, Westworld, Donald Trump, free will, rationality, conspiracy thinking, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_56_Paul_Bloom.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>134658720</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#55 — Islamism vs Secularism</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Shadi Hamid about the power of religious belief, the failure of the Left, Islamist democracy, free speech, profiling, white nationalism, Obama’s foreign policy and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_55_Shadi_Hamid.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>150661333</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#54 — Trumping The World</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with journalist James Kirchick about the coming Trump presidency, liberalism vs illiberalism, fake news, Russia, Syria, Iran, and the future of American power.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_54_James_Kirchick.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>79119778</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#53 — The Dawn of Artificial Intelligence</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with computer scientist Stuart Russell about the challenge of building artificial intelligence that is compatible with human well-being.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_53_Stuart_Russell.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>73449760</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#52 — Finding Our Way in the Cosmos</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with physicist David Deutsch about the foundations of knowledge, the moral landscape, possible futures for conscious beings, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_52_David_Deutsch.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>105343205</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#51 — The Most Powerful Clown</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris talks about the results of the 2016 presidential election and the prospects of a President Trump.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_51_Most_Powerful_Clown.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>29598265</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#50 — The Borders of Tolerance</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Ayaan Hirsi Ali about Islamism, the migrant crisis in Europe, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_50_Ayaan_Hirsi_Ali.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>57161517</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#49 — The Lesser Evil</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Andrew Sullivan about the 2016 presidential election.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_49_Andrew_Sullivan.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>141653519</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#48 — What Is Moral Progress?</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with philosopher Peter Singer about the foundations of morality, expanding the circle of our moral concern, politics, free speech, conspiracy thinking, Edward Snowden, the importance of intentions, WWII, euthanasia, eating “happy cows,” and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_48_Peter_Singer.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>113560879</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#47 — The Frontiers of Political Correctness</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Gad Saad about political correctness, academic taboos, Islam, immigration, Donald Trump, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_47_Gad_Saad.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>107855116</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#46 — The End of Faith Sessions 3</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris reads and discusses the third chapter of "The End of Faith." Topics covered: Christianity, Judaism, the Inquisition, witchcraft, anti-Semitism, and the Holocaust.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_46_The_End_of_Faith_3.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>63677465</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#45 — Ask Me Anything 5</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris answers questions from listeners about how 9/11 changed his life, Brazilian jiu-jitsu, free will, why he podcasts, Milo and the alt-Right, identity politics, Clinton vs. Trump, vegetarianism, and the Hannibal Buress episode.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_45_AMA_5.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>77908622</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#44 — Being Good and Doing Good</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Oxford philosopher William MacAskill about effective altruism, moral illusions, existential risk, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_44_William_MacAskill.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>125794870</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#43 — What Do Jihadists Really Want?</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris reads from the latest issue of "Dabiq," the magazine of ISIS, and discusses the beliefs and goals of jihadists worldwide.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_43_Dabiq.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>47425569</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#42 — Racism and Violence in America</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris talks to economist Glenn C. Loury about racism, police violence, the Black Lives Matter movement, and related topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_42_Glenn_C_Loury.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>122046432</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#41 — Faith in Reason</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Eric Weinstein about the relationship between faith and reason and about some of the factors that make conversations on important topics so difficult.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_41_Eric_Weinstein.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>138947577</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#40 — Complexity &amp; Stupidity</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris talks to biologist David Krakauer about information, complex systems, and the future of humanity.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_40_David_Krakauer.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>99530417</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#39 — Free Will Revisited</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with philosopher Daniel Dennett about free will.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_39_Daniel_Dennett.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>100704925</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#38 — The End of Faith Sessions 2</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris reads and discusses the second chapter of "The End of Faith." However, the first hour of this podcast focuses on Donald Trump, Hillary Clinton, and the political implications of the recent terrorist attack in Orlando. Discussion of The End of Faith begins at 1:04:30.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_38_The_End_of_Faith_2.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>153837038</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#37 — Thinking in Public</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with astrophysicist Neil deGrasse Tyson about the public understanding of science, his career as an educator, political atheism, racism, artificial intelligence, alien life, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_37_Neil_deGrasse_Tyson.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>100975710</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#36 — What Makes Us Safer?</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with a leading expert on homeland security about the war on terror, profiling, Islamism, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_36_What_Makes_Us_Safer.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>80134970</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#35 — The End Of Faith Sessions 1</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris reads and discusses the first chapter of "The End of Faith."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_35_The_End_of_Faith_1.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>116700166</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#34 — The Light of the Mind</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with philosopher David Chalmers about the nature of consciousness, the challenges of understanding it scientifically, and the prospect that we will one day build it into our machines.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_34_David_Chalmers.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>101213377</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#33 — Ask Me Anything 4</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris answers questions from listeners about the recent attacks in Brussels, dealing with anxiety, the science of immortality, fame, liberalism, the Golden Age of Islam, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_33_AMA_4.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>56510095</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#32 — The Best Podcast Ever</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris talks to Omer Aziz about Islam, Islamism, free speech, and related topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_32_Omer_Aziz.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>203660639</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#31 — Evolving Minds</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris responds to Omer Aziz and Salon magazine, and then speaks with Jonathan Haidt about the scientific study of morality, the problem of political correctness, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_31_Jonathan_Haidt.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>113879397</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#30 — Inside the Crucible</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris briefly revisits the Apple-FBI controversy and then speaks with Michael Weiss about ISIS and the ongoing civil war in Syria. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_30_Michael_Weiss.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>105654898</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#29 — Throw Open the Gates</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris responds to criticism of his views on the Apple-FBI controversy and then speaks with Maryam Namazie about friendly fire among secularists, profiling, the immigration crisis in Europe, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_29_Maryam_Namazie.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>122606352</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#28 — Meat Without Misery</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris offers a few more thoughts on Clinton vs Sanders, as well as on the ethics of strong encryption. He then speaks with Uma Valeti, cardiologist and CEO of Memphis Meats, about the future of food production. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_28_Uma_Valeti.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>65134615</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#27 — Ask Me Anything 3</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris answers questions from listeners about free will, meditation, Noam Chomsky, the illusion of the self, Clinton vs. Sanders, the de-platforming of Richard Dawkins, wealth inequality, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_27_AMA_3.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>68103453</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#26 — The Logic of Violence</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with retired Navy SEAL and author, Jocko Willink. They discuss U.S. foreign policy, war, human evil, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_26_Jocko_Willink.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>101904920</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#25 — Behind the Gun</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with former SWAT operator and lead weapons and tactics instructor for the LAPD Metro Division, Scott Reitz. They discuss guns, gun control, police violence, and related topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_25_Scott_Reitz.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>100483161</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#24 — Ask Me Anything 2</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris answers questions from listeners about Islamism, free will, honesty, vegetarianism, why he doesn’t publish more in academic journals, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_24_AMA_2.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>89914831</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#23 — Islam and the Future of Tolerance (Audiobook Excerpts)</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris introduces the audio edition of his book with Maajid Nawaz, "Islam and the Future of Tolerance: A Dialogue."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_23_Maajid_Nawaz.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>69876794</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#22 — Surviving the Cosmos</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris talks to physicist David Deutsch about the reach and power of human knowledge, the future of artificial intelligence, and the survival of civilization.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_22_David_Deutsch.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>109523194</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#21 — On the Maintenance of Civilization</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with author Douglas Murray about Islamism, liberalism, civil society, and the migrant crisis in Europe.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_21_Douglas_Murray.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>127288940</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#20 — Still Sleepwalking Toward Armageddon</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris reflects on the recent terrorist attacks in Paris.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_20_Sleepwalking_Toward_Armageddon.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>23381480</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#19 — The Riddle Of The Gun (Revisited)</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up Podcast, Sam Harris discusses his views about guns and gun control in light of a recent mass shooting.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_19_Riddle_Of_The_Gun_Revisited.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>92728282</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#18 — The Multiverse &amp; You (&amp; You &amp; You &amp; You...)</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with MIT cosmologist Max Tegmark about the foundations of science, our current understanding of the universe, and the risks of future breakthroughs in artificial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_18_Max_Tegmark.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>83708601</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#17 — What I Really Think About Profiling</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris responds to misrepresentations of his views (again).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_17_What_I_Really_Think_About_Profiling.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>13338457</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#16 — The Dark Side</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris and Paul Bloom talk about Donald Trump, torture, trophy hunting, and other terrors.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_16_Paul_Bloom.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>95005880</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#15 — Questions Along the Path</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris and Joseph Goldstein discuss the practice of meditation and answer questions that came from listeners in response to their first conversation, "The Path and the Goal."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_15_Joseph_Goldstein.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>96228913</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#14 — The Virtues of Cold Blood</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with psychologist Paul Bloom about the limitations of empathy as a guide to moral reasoning.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_14_Paul_Bloom.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>87533757</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#13 — The Moral Gaze</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with the filmmaker Joshua Oppenheimer about his remarkable documentaries, "The Act of Killing" and "The Look of Silence."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_13_Joshua_Oppenheimer.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>68801531</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#12 — Leaving the Church</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode, Sam Harris speaks with Megan Phelps-Roper, granddaughter of Fred Phelps of the infamous Westboro Baptist Church.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_12_Megan_Phelps-Roper.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>72061264</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#11 — Shouldering the Burden of History</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode, Sam Harris and Dan Carlin (host of the Hardcore History and Common Sense podcasts) discuss American interventionism, the war on terror, and related topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_11_Dan_Carlin.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>123154418</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#10 — Faith vs. Fact</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode, Sam Harris interviews biologist Jerry Coyne about his new book, "Faith vs. Fact: Why Science and Religion are Incompatible."&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_10_Jerry_Coyne.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>64481126</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#9 — Final Thoughts On Chomsky</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;Sam Harris reflects on his failure to have a productive conversation with Noam Chomsky.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_9_Thoughts_On_Chomsky.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>11009172</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#8 — Ask Me Anything 1</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up Podcast, Sam Harris talks about atheism, artificial intelligence, rape, public speaking, meditation, consciousness, free will, intellectual honesty, and other topics.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_8_AMA_1.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>67500883</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#7 — Through the Eyes of a Cult</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris discusses the Heaven's Gate suicide cult and argues that we all have something important to learn from them about the power of belief.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_7_Cults.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>30170854</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#6 — The Chapel Hill Murders and 'Militant' Atheism</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;Sam Harris responds to the charge that "militant" atheism is responsible for the murder of three Muslim students in North Carolina.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_6_Chapel_Hill.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>24395428</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#5 — After Charlie Hebdo and Other Thoughts</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;Sam Harris answers reader questions in the wake of the terrorist attacks in Paris.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_5_Charlie_Hebdo.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>38582717</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#4 — The Path and the Goal</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Waking Up podcast, Sam Harris speaks with Joseph Goldstein about the practice of meditation.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_4_Joseph_Goldstein.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>120181961</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#3 — WAKING UP — Chapter One</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;This is the complete first chapter of Waking Up: A Guide to Spirituality Without Religion by Sam Harris.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;To purchase the audiobook: &lt;a href= "http://amzn.to/1v1NEIK"&gt;http://amzn.to/1v1NEIK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;To purchase the print edition: &lt;a href= "http://amzn.to/1mqiAKL"&gt;http://amzn.to/1mqiAKL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_3_Waking_Up_Chapter_1.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>83627525</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#2 — Why Don't I Criticize Israel?</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;In the wake of the recent war in Gaza, many readers have asked "Why don't you criticize Israel?" Here is my response. You can read an annotated transcript of this podcast at: http://www.samharris.org/blog/item/why-dont-i-criticize-israel&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/160522369-samharrisorg-why-dont-i-criticize-israel.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>16679709</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>#1 — Drugs And The Meaning Of Life</Titel>
      <Description>&lt;p&gt;The full text of this essay can be read here:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href= "http://www.samharris.org/blog/item/drugs-and-the-meaning-of-life"&gt;http://www.samharris.org/blog/item/drugs-and-the-meaning-of-life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can support the Waking Up podcast at &lt;a href= "https://www.samharris.org/support"&gt;samharris.org/support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/Waking_Up_1_Drugs_And_The_Meaning_Of_Life.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>20556491</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>How to talk to a Christian</Titel>
      <Description>This is an edited excerpt from remarks that Sam Harris made in a debate with a Christian apologist at Notre Dame University in 2011. The full debate can be viewed here: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yqaHXKLRKzg</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/119722601-samharrisorg-how-to-talk-to-a-christian.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>15026540</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>Looking for the Self (26 Minutes)</Titel>
      <Description>This is a 26-minute mindfulness meditation, led by Sam Harris. For more information visit www.samharris.org.</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/112643459-samharrisorg-mindfulness-meditation-26.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>50359138</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
   <Avsnitt>
      <Titel>Mindfulness Meditation (9 Minutes)</Titel>
      <Description>This is a 9-minute mindfulness meditation, led by Sam Harris. For more information visit www.samharris.org.</Description>
      <URI>http://traffic.libsyn.com/wakingup/112643452-samharrisorg-mindfulness-meditation-9.mp3?dest-id=480596</URI>
      <Length>17071196</Length>
   </Avsnitt>
</Kategorier>